clickforward.com 2006-06-18

# Click Forward | Privacy Policy

### Click Forward Marketing Privacy Statement

Click Forward Marketing is committed to protecting your privacy. This Click Forward Marketing Privacy Statement applies to data collection and usage on Click Forward Marketing sites and services.

Click Forward Marketing is an interactive marketing company. Personal information of all users is collected, used and disclosed as described in this Privacy Statement.

### Collection of your Personal Information

At some sites, Click Forward Marketing collects personal information, such as your e-mail address, name, home or work address or telephone number. Click Forward Marketing may also collect demographic information, such as your ZIP code, age, gender, preferences, interests and favorites.

If you choose to sign up for a paid service, we will collect additional personal information, including your credit card number and billing address, in order to create a Click Forward Marketing billing account.

Click Forward Marketing may collect information about your visit, including the pages you view, the links you click and other actions taken within Click Forward Marketing. We also collect certain standard information that your browser sends to every website you visit, such as your IP address, browser type and language, access times and referring Web site addresses.

Certain Click Forward Marketing services may be co-branded and offered in conjunction with another company. If you register for or use such services, both Click Forward Marketing and the other company may receive information collected in conjunction with the co-branded services.

### Use of your Personal Information

Click Forward Marketing collects and uses your personal information to operate Click Forward Marketing and deliver the services you have requested. These services may include the display of customized content and advertising based upon the information Click Forward Marketing has collected.

Click Forward Marketing does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. Click Forward Marketing does not use or disclose sensitive personal information, such as race, religion, or political affiliations, without your explicit consent.

Click Forward Marketing may access and/or disclose your personal information if required to do so by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Click Forward Marketing; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Click Forward Marketing; or (c) act in urgent circumstances to protect the personal safety of users of Click Forward Marketing services or members of the public.

Personal information collected on this site may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Click Forward Marketing or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities, and by using this site, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. Click Forward Marketing abides by the safe harbor framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of data from the European Union.

### Control of your Personal Information

You may subscribe and unsubscribe to Click Forward Marketing Newsletters. In addition, each Click Forward Marketing newsletter you receive will have instructions on how to unsubscribe prominently mentioned in it.

### Security of your Personal Information

Click Forward Marketing is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of security technologies and procedures to help protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. For example, we store the personal information you provide on computer systems with limited access, which are located in controlled facilities. When we transmit highly confidential information (such as a credit card number) over the Internet, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol.

### Use of Web Beacons

Click Forward Marketing Web pages may contain electronic images known as Web beacons - sometimes called single-pixel gifs - that allow Click Forward Marketing to count users who have visited those pages and to deliver co-branded services. Click Forward Marketing may include Web beacons in promotional e-mail messages or Click Forward Marketing Newsletters in order to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon.

### Enforcement of this Privacy Statement

If you have questions regarding this statement, you should first contact Click Forward Marketing via e-mail.

### Changes to this Statement

Click Forward Marketing will occasionally update this Privacy Statement to reflect company and customer feedback. If there are material changes to this Statement or in how Click Forward Marketing will use your personal information, Click Forward Marketing will prominently post such changes prior to implementing the change. Click Forward Marketing encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Click Forward Marketing is protecting your information.
